{
    "id": "c6c9f80864664024b5899dc6b8da828d",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "When I opened my eyes, I ………………. a strange sight.",
            "description": "We use the simple past tense to talk about two quickly finished actions in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "saw",
                "was seeing",
                "have seen"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "28ace9d352d447e5874baf6822bdd9de"
        },
        {
            "question": "Every morning she …………….. up early and gets ready for work.",
            "description": "We use the simple present tense to talk about habits and routines.",
            "answers": [
                "is waking",
                "wakes",
                "has woken"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b37877cdc4df4fe7bf7e82349445762a"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I knew what he wanted, I ………………. this.",
            "description": "We use the second conditional to talk about imaginary situations. In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will not permit",
                "would not permit",
                "would not have permitted"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "77dfa40b40f3477d9ad46c78e8f7ba19"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………….. anything from her in a long time.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "didn't hear",
                "haven't heard",
                "am not hearing"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b654206ee5d64c459c4cb829e837252d"
        },
        {
            "question": "The headmaster ……………… to talk to you.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about facts. ",
            "answers": [
                "want",
                "wants",
                "is wanting"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f996ef0245274d45b6f47223a0ca66f5"
        },
        {
            "question": "Jane ………………. with her parents.",
            "description": "We use the simple present to talk about permanent situations.",
            "answers": [
                "is living",
                "lives",
                "has lived"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c7286cd4fa7f41399dac31da1c067701"
        },
        {
            "question": "We ..................... Greece next month.",
            "description": "The present continuous tense can be used to talk about future events if the arrangement already exists. ",
            "answers": [
                "visit",
                "will visit",
                "would visit",
                "are visiting"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "076d4d12d5914623aade104865be398b"
        },
        {
            "question": "The moon …………….. around the earth.",
            "description": "We use the simple present to talk about facts and general truths.",
            "answers": [
                "is revolving",
                "has revolved",
                "revolves"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "2fd7882254e14df08bd5a20bf9d0d1ce"
        },
        {
            "question": "She ………………… a novel.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect here because there is no reference to time.",
            "answers": [
                "wrote",
                "writes",
                "has written"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9ba685c2c6934a6ca3c723625e3a8373"
        },
        {
            "question": "All students ………………. in their work.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "handed",
                "have handed",
                "hand"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "56001882c9294b468408988f5913c7c2"
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………. English for twelve years.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect continuous tense to talk about actions and situations that started in the past and have continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "am teaching",
                "have been teaching",
                "will be teaching"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c04f622ccff54fd4b423ea219849c49e"
        },
        {
            "question": "The students ............................. their dialogues.",
            "description": "We use the present continuous to talk about actions and situations that are going on at the moment of speaking. ",
            "answers": [
                "rehearse",
                "are rehearsing",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "7bce28619fb94942b8ba9d8b92029bd9"
        }
    ]
}